[Music]
hello all the global coronavirus crisis
has led to some interesting developments
for the Indian fixed income markets
number one crude oil has come down by
$35 per barrel every dollar that crude
oil comes down leads to a benefit of
12,000 crores for India so the $35
correction leads to a gain of 4 lakh
20,000 crores for India which means a
gain of almost 35,000 crores per month
for India
the bank has four hundred and eighty
billion dollars of foreign exchange
reserve in the last 15 days the rupee
has depreciated by four rupees against
US dollar so this leads to an m2m of
almost two lakh crores to Reserve Bank
which is a nun booked profit in the
Reserve Bank's book of almost 2 lakh
crores so these two are significant
macroeconomic positives from an India
point of view the high prices of potato
onion and tomato about 4-5 months back
resulted in a situation where interest
rates stopped going down in India and
now we think that in the April Reserve
Bank meeting there should be a big drop
in interest rates so this means that
with a 1 month view there is a very very
good chance of good rate cuts in April
monetary policy meeting and therefore
with the elevated corporate credit
spreads that exist there is good scope
for very interesting investment
opportunity in all corporate credit
papers at this point of time and all the
short duration papers that invests in
many of the short duration fixed income
funds are likely to benefit out of this
so we think that investors should not
panic at this point of time and redeem
from any fixed income mutual funds which
are focused on the short term fixed
income space and in fact in
should actually load into short-term
fixed income mutual funds by actually
increasing their investments in the
short term fixed income space ahead of
March 31st because they are likely to
benefit out of the rate cuts which are
likely in the April monetary policy
statement the current investment
opportunity is large in the context of
the big drops in global interest rates
which have happened out after the
coronaviruses crisis it is very rare
that a big central branch like us will
cut interest rates by 1.5 percent in a
month and global fixed income market
like us has seen dramatic drop in
10-year US Treasuries leading to a very
very low interest rates there so the
opportunity in short term corporate
credits and short term products in the
Indian mutual fund space in the fixed
income market is very large and we
request investors to consider investing
in them and also not panic at this point
of time and take out money from any
fixed income mutual fund in the next 10
15 days thank you mutual fund
investments are subject to market risks
read all scheme related documents
carefully